# GUSTAVO PEREIRA

WEB DEVELOPER

Email: xgustavux@hotmail.com Website: gustavupp.github.io

Mobile: 490 532 668

Address: 417B Kessels Road, Robertson QLD - 4109

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u>



## **ABOUT ME**

Throughout my childhood, I used to spend hours drawing pencil portraits. That used to put me in a flow state that I consider one of the best pleasures one can experience. Years later I found out that I get in the same flow state when coding. I must admit, it is addictive.

Software development for me is not just a job, it offers me engaging challenges to continually learn and improve my skills. It's what I do for work as well as for leisure.

Below you'll find projects I've completed recently that showcase the skills I've acquired so far.

### RECENT PROJECTS

Pocket Bookshelf Web App 2.0 | React Developer > Check Live
DEC 2021 - JAN 2021

- Rewrote Pocket Bookshelf 1.0's front-end with React JS for a more maintainable and scalable web app.
- Utilized Redux to manage global state and React Router for navigation
- Implemented user authentication with Auth0
- Used SASS for modular and more readable CSS.
- Created a NodeJs server using Express and MySQL to persist the user's list of books.

### Asil E-commerce | React Developer > Check Live

DEC 2021 - JAN 2021

- Wrote maintainable and reusable code using the latest ES6 JavaScript and React hooks.
- Utilized React's Context API to manage global state and React Router for navigation
- Implemented user authentication with Auth0 and Stripe as a payment gateway
- CommerceJs handles the back-end(cart, checkout tokens, email delivery, inventory, etc) with which we interact via its awesome API

# Pocket Bookshelf Web App 1.0 | JavaScript Developer > Check Live NOV 2021 - DEC 2021

- Written in Vanilla JavaScript only using functional programming paradigm (with ES6 Modules for better-organized code)
- Used asynchronous JavaScript to fetch data from Google Books API and NY Times
   API
- · Utilized web storage API to persist date in the user's browser
- · Added .env variables with Webpack to hide API Keys

### **TECH SKILLS**

HTML5
CSS3
JavaScript ES6
React Js
SASS
Git
REDUX
AJAX
NODE JS
SQL
jQuery
Express
Bootstrap
REST API

### **NON TECH**

Communication
Team Oriented
Reliable
Ponctual
Accountable
Self-Motivated
Costumer Service

- Created a dynamic menu filtered by categories using ES6 high order functions (reduce, filter, forEach, map)
- Used media queries, CSS FlexBox/Grid to create a fully responsive Website
- Implemented dynamic navbar using the .getBoundingClientRect method
- Used pageYOffset method to change the navbar's position (static to fixed) when scrolling.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Digital Marketer | Crank Indoor Climbing (Part-time)
FEB 2019 - Present

- Create, Manage and optimize Google Search Ads campaigns for the highest ROI, based on extensive keyword research.
- Creation of custom targeted publics for specific promotions.
- WordPress website content management and SEO best practices
- Email marketing campaigns and landing page creation

Flight Attendant, | Gol Airlines FEB 2011 - JAN 2019

- Known for exceptional customer service and top-notch friendliness.
- · Skilled at responding to emergency situations and remaining cool under pressure
- Clearly explained and demonstrated safety procedures for up to 200 passengers
- · Reassured and comforted passengers during unavoidable delays and turbulent flights

IT Support Technician, | CTIS Tecnologia S/A FEB 2009 - FEB 2011

- · Assisting users in person and remotely with hardware and software-related concerns
- Utilized technical training to resolve concerns related to software and hardware functionality
- Walked customers through step-by-step processes for troubleshooting hardware issues.
- Used good problem-solving skills for troubleshooting problems.

# **FORMAL EDUCATION**

Universidade Nove de Julho, São Paulo, Brazill | Bachelor of Translation And Interpreting JUL 2013 - JUL 2016

Universidade Nove de Julho, São Paulo, Brazil | Certificate III In Information Technology JAN 2009 - JUL 2010